Guide to the Recordsings of Sunrise Semester Programs RG.7.3.1.1
New York University Archives
- "The New Consciousness: Latin American Literature in Translation" with Associate Professor John Coleman, December, 1971 - March, 1972
  - Episode #35, December 13, 1971 (Box 362, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0385)
  - Video recording, March 6, 1972; cuid18682 (Box 272, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0447)
- "Immigrants", May, 1972 - July, 1973
  - Episode #10, May 29, 1972 (Box 31, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0403)
  - Episode #47, July 17, 1973; cuid18689 (Box 32, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0411)
- "Cold War", June - July, 1972
  - Video recording, June 26, 1972; cuid18683 (Box 28, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0572)
  - Video recording, July 26, 1972; cuid18684 (Box 29, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0505)
- "Twentieth-Century American Art" with Lecturer Ruth Bowman, November, 1972
  - Episode #40, November 20, 1972; cuid18686 (Box 307, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0487)
  - Episode #43, November 28, 1972; cuid18687 (Box 308, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0577)
- "Cities", July - August, 1972
  - Episode #32, August 2, 1972 (Box 27, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0416)
  - Video recording, August 18, 1972 (Box 30, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0575)
- "Law and Morality" with Professor Graham Hughes, November - December, 1972
  - Video recording, November 15, 1972 (Box 306, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0428)
  - Episode #43, December 13, 1972 (Box 309, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0488)
- "The Heavenly Twins: Astronomy and Astrology" with Professor Engelbert Schucking, February, 1973
  - Episode #14, February 15, 1973
    - Original recording (Box 311, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0160)
    - Access DVDs (Box 14, Dvd 11:48-11:49)
  - Episode #15, February 22, 1973
    - Original recording, cuid18731 (Box 314, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0144)
    - Access DVDs (Box 14, Dvd 11:50-11:51)
- "Personality Theory and Creativity" with Professor Morris Stein, February, 1973
  - Episode #11, February, 1973 (Box 310, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0171)
  - Episode #12, February 20, 1973 (Box 312, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0546)
- "Hispanic", May, 1973 - June, 1980
  - Episode #2, May 7, 1973 (Box 342, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0419)
  - Episode #5, May 14, 1973 (Box 341, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0509)
  - Episode #23, June 2, 1980 (Box 343, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0427)
  - Episode #26, undated (Box 18, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0170)
- "Twentieth-Century Literature: Its Past and Perfect" with Professor Floyd Zulli, September - October, 1973
  - Episode #6, September 12, 1973 (Box 315, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0393)
  - Episode #16, October 9, 1973 (Box 316, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0518)
- "The World of Islam" with Professor Francis Peters, October, 1973
  - Episode #45, October 16, 1973 (Box 317, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0571)
  - Episode #27, October 17, 1973 (Box 318, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0552)
- "Practical Reasoning" with Associate Professor Robert Gurland, March, 1974
  - "Reasoning", November, 1973 - November 1997 (Box 7, Vhs 7.3.1.1.0387)
  - Video recording, March 18, 1974 (Box 321, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0520)
  - Episode #38, March 26, 1974 (Box 322, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0413)
- "The Media in America" with Professor John Tebbel, February - March, 1974
  - Episode #26, February 20, 1974 (Box 319, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0161)
  - Episode #32, March 6, 1974 (Box 320, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0408)
- "Presidents", June - July, 1974
  - Episode #39, June 24, 1974; cuid18690 (Box 33, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0490)
  - Episode #50, July 1, 1974; cuid18691 (Box 34, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0471)
- "Health", July, 1974 - July, 1979
  - Episode #38, July 2, 1979 (Box 35, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0457)
  - Episode #39, July 10, 1974; cuid18692 (Box 36, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0477)
- "The Meaning of Death" with Associate Professor James Carse -- Episode #5, September 13, 1974 (Box 345, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0450)
- "History of African Civilization" with Associate Professor Richard Hull, October - November, 1974
  - Episode #33, October 9, 1974 (Box 346, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0545)
  - Episode #39, November 19, 1974 (Box 347, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0478)
- "Music of the Romantic Era" with Professor Elaine Brody, January - April, 1975
  - Episode #6, January 15, 1975 (Box 349, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0519)
  - Episode #37, April 2, 1975 (Box 351, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0576)
- "The Near East in Modern Times" with Professor L. Carl Brown, January - April, 1975
  - Video recording, January 30, 1975 (Box 350, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0484)
  - Episode #41, April 7, 1975 (Box 352, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0496)
- "Science", March, 1975
  - Episode #4, March 21, 1975 (Box 38, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0470)
  - Episode #22, March 21, 1975; cuid18693 (Box 37, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0468)
- "Population", July, 1975
  - Episode #93, July 9, 1975 (Box 327, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0455)
  - Episode #100, July 15, 1975 (Box 328, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0458)
- "Anthropology of the Middle East and North Africa" with Professor Dr. Dale Eickelman, September - October, 1975
  - Episode #5, September 8, 1975 (Box 353, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0534)
  - Episode #17, October 4, 1975 (Box 355, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0401)
- "Magic, Faith, and Healing" with Professor Dr. Ari Kiev, September - October, 1975
  - Episode #2, September 9, 1975 (Box 354, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0472)
  - Episode #18, October 4, 1975 (Box 356, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0549)
- "Presidential Power and the American Dream" with Professor Louis Koenig, January - February, 1976
  - Video recording, January 20, 1976; cuid18694 (Box 39, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0527)
  - Video recording, February 17, 1976; cuid18697 (Box 43, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0507)
- "Reading and the Individual: Diagnostic Teaching of Reading in the Classroom" with Professor George Manolakes, February, 1976
  - Episode #11, February 9, 1976; cuid18696 (Box 42, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0466)
  - Episode #13, February 9, 1976; cuid18695 (Box 41, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0476)
- "Transition", April - May, 1976
  - Episode #3, April 7, 1976 (Box 329, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0414)
  - Episode #7, May 12, 1976 (Box 324, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0432)
- "Society", May, 1976
  - Episode #21, May 26, 1976 (Box 326, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0395)
  - Episode #33, May 24, 1976 (Box 325, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0394)
- "The Novel and Theatre of Contemporary France" with Professor Tom Bishop, September - October, 1976
  - Episode #13, September 20, 1976 (Box 357, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0459)
  - Episode #27, October 18, 1976 (Box 359, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0521)
- "Communication, The Invisible Environment" with Professor Neil Postman, September 28, 1976 - January 7, 1977; cuid18789
  - Episode #9, "Our World of Assumptions", September 28, 1976
    Air date: October 8, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18732 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0277)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:18)
  - Episode #10, October 5, 1976 (Box 358, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0409)
  - Episode #11, "Different Uses and Functions of Language", October 13, 1976
    Air date: October 13, 1976; Recording date unknown.
    - Original recording, cuid18733 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0278)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:19)
  - Episode #12, "Levels of Abstraction", October 5, 1976
    Air date: October 15, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18734 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0279)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:20)
  - Episode #13, "Language as a Metaphor" (Part I), October 12, 1976
    Air date: October 18, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18735 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0280)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:21)
  - Episode #14, "Language as a Metaphor" (Part II), October 12, 1976
    Air date: October 20, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18736 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0281)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:22)
  - Episode #15, "Application and Discussion of Language as Metaphor", October 12, 1976
    Air date: October 22, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18737 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0254)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:52)
  - Episode #16, "Language Breakdowns Within Ourselves", October 19, 1976
    Air date: October 25, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18738 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0282)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:23)
  - Episode #17, "More About Language Breakdowns", October 19, 1976
    Air date: October 27, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18739 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0271)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:24)
  - Episode #18, "Discussion of Language Breakdowns", October 19, 1976
    Air date: October 29, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18740 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0270)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:25)
  - Episode #19, "Introduction to Interpersonal Communication", October 25, 1976
    Air date: November 1, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18741 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0269)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:26)
  - Episode #20, "The Dramaturgical Model", October 25, 1976
    Air date: November 3, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18742 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0268)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:27)
  - Episode #21, "Discussion of Interpersonal Communication", October 25, 1976
    Air date: November 5, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18743 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0267)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:28)
  - Episode #22, "Hidden Rules of Public Behavior", October 26, 1976
    Air date: November 8, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18744 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0276)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:29)
  - Episode #23, "More About Hidden Rules of Public Behavior", October 26, 1976
    Air date: November 12, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18745 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0275)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:30)
  - Episode #24, "Hidden Rules of Public Behavior", October 26, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18746 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0274)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:31)
  - Episode #25, "Introduction to Mass Communication", November 9, 1976
    Air date: November 15, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18747 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0256)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:53)
  - Episode #26, "A Discussion of the History of the Media" (Part I), November 4-9, 1976
    Air date: November 17, 1976
    - Original audio recording, November 4, 1976; cuid18748 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0272)
    - Video recording, November 9, 1976 (Box 360, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0448)
    - Access CD, November 4, 1976 (Box 14, Cd 6:32)
  - Episode #27, "A Discussion of the History of the Media" (Part II), November 9, 1976
    Air date: November 19, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18749 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0273)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:33)
  - Episode #28, "Historical Perspectives on Media Change" (Part I), November 16, 1976
    Air date: November 24, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18750 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0253)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:34)
  - Episode #29, "Historical Perspectives on Media Change" (Part II), November 16, 1976
    Air date: November 26, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18751 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0247)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:35)
  - Episode #30, "Print As A Communication Environment", November 16, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18752 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0248)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:36)
  - Episode #31, "Print As A Communication Environment", November 23, 1976
    Air date: November 29, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18753 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0249)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:37)
  - Episode #32, "Television as a Communication Environment" (Part I), November 23, 1976
    Air date: December 1, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18754 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0250)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:38)
  - Episode #33, "Television as a Communication Environment" (Part II), November 23, 1976
    Air date: December 5, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18755 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0262)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:39)
  - Episode #34, "Television Framing", November 30, 1976
    Air date: December 6, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18756 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0260)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:40)
  - Episode #35, "Television Commercials as a Communication Environment" (Part I), November 30, 1976
    Air date: December 10, 1976
    - Original audio recording, cuid18757 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0259)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:41)
    - Access DVD (Box 14, Dvd 13:4)
  - Episode #36, "Television Commercials as a Communication Environment" (Part II), November 30, 1976
    - Original audio recording, cuid18758 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0258)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:42)
    - Access DVD (Box 14, Dvd 13:5)
  - Episode #40, "The Tyranny of Technique", December 10, 1976
    Air date: December 20, 1976
    - Original recording (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0252)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:43)
  - Episode #41, "Movies as a Communication Environment" (Part I), December 10, 1976
    Air date: December 22, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18759 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0251)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:44)
  - Episode #42, "Movies as a Communication Environment" (Part II), December 10, 1976
    Air date: December 24, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18760 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0261)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:45)
  - Episode #43, "The Telephone as a Communication Environment", December 14, 1976
    Air date: December 27, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18761 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0263)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:46)
  - Episode #44, "Radio as a Communication Environment", December 14, 1976
    Air date: December 29, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18762 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0265)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:47)
  - Episode #45, "A Discussion of Additional Media", December 13, 1976
    Air date: December 31, 1976
    - Original recording, cuid18763 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0266)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:48)
  - Episode #46, "Communication Principles", December 15, 1976
    Air date: January 3, 1977
    - Original recording, cuid18764 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0257)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:49)
  - Episode #47, "Educational Application", December 15, 1976
    Air date: January 5, 1977
    - Original recording, cuid18765 (Box 4, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0264)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:50)
  - Episode #48, "Personal Summaries", December 15, 1976
    Air date: January 7, 1977
    - Original recording, cuid18766 (Box 3, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0255)
    - Access CD (Box 14, Cd 6:51)
  - "Television Commercials as a Communications Environment", December 12, 1976; cuid18787
    - Original video recording, cuid18795 (Box 7, Half inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0388)
    - Access DVD (Box 14, Dvd 13:4)
  - "Television News as a Communication Form", December 17, 1976; cuid18788
    - Original video recording, cuid18796 (Box 7, Half inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0391)
    - Access DVD (Box 14, Dvd 13:5)
  - "The TV Frame", undated; cuid18786
    - Original video recording, cuid18797 (Box 7, Half inch video reel 7.3.1.1.0390)
    - Access DVD (Box 14, Dvd 13:6)
- "Religions and Civilizations of the Near East" with Professor Dr. Bernard Lewis, February, 1977
  - Video recording "7042", February 15, 1977 (Box 58, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0168)
  - Video recording "7880", February 15, 1977 (Box 59, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0461)
- "Latin America", March, 1977
  - Episode #13, March 29, 1977 (Box 335, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0430)
  - Episode #14, March 29, 1977 (Box 336, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0522)
- "Teaching the Learning Disabled" with Professor Dr. Kim Reid, March, 1977
  - #7047, March 2, 1977 (Box 330, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0516)
  - #7061, March 23, 1977 (Box 331, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0402)
- "Aging", July, 1977
  - Episode #43, July 12, 1977 (Box 333, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0431)
  - Episode #49, July 12, 1977 (Box 334, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0570)
- "Discipline in the Classroom: Social and Emotional Problems" with Professor Dr. Lawrence Balter, September 21, 1977 - January 6, 1978
  - Episode #1, September 12, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0323)
    Air date: September 19, 1977
  - Episode #2, September 12, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0316)
    Air date: September 21, 1977
  - Episode #3, "Children Offer Opinions", September 12, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0283)
    Air date: September 23, 1977
  - Episode #4, "Discipline and the Young Child", September 23, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0314)
    Air date: September 26, 1977
  - Episode #5, "Child Study: Developmental Concepts, Part I", September 23, 1977 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0325)
    Guest lecturer: Dr. Louis Lauro; Air date: September 28,1977
  - Episode #6, "Child Study: Developmental Concepts, Part II", September 23, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0310)
    Guest lecturer: Dr. Louis Lauro; Air date: September 30, 1977
  - Episode #7, "Child Study: Developmental Concepts, Part III", September 26, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0305)
    Guest lecturer: "Dr. Louis Lauro"; Air date: October 3, 1977
  - Episode #8, "Child Study: Developmental Concepts, Part IV", September 26, 1977 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0322)
    Guest lecturer: Dr. Louis Lauro; Air date: October 5, 1977
  - Episode #8, September 26, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0303)
  - Episode #9, "Jean Piaget: Theory Reviewed", September 26, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0319)
    Air date: October 7, 1977
  - Episode #10, "Social Perspective Taking", October 3, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0289)
    Air date: October 10, 1977
  - Episode #11, "Moral Judgment", October 3, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0288)
    Air date: October 12, 1977
  - Episode #12, "Moral Development: Psychodynamic Considerations", October 3, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0299)
    Air date: October 14, 1977
  - Episode #13, "Introduction to Reward and Punishment", October 13, 1977 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0320)
    Air date: October 17, 1977
  - Episode #15, "Children's Rights, Part II", October 13, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0306)
    Guest lecturer: Dr. Don Bersoff; Air date: October 21, 1977
  - Episode #16, "Legal Matters", October 10, 1977 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0324)
    Guest lecturer: Robert McKay; Air date: October 24, 1977
  - Episode #17, "Corporal Punishment, Part I", October 10, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0286)
    Guest lecturer: Dr. Irwin Hyman; Air date: October 26, 1977
  - Episode #18, "Corporal Punishment, Part II", October 10, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0313)
    Guest lecturer: Dr. Irwin Hyman; Air date: October 28, 1977
  - Episode #19, October 17, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0298)
    Guest lecturer: Dr. Stephen Wilder; Air date: October 31, 1977
  - Episode #20, "Learning Theory: Relevant Concepts", November 2, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0304)
    Guest lecturer: Dr. Paul Wachtel; Air date: November 2, 1977; Recording date unknown
  - Episode #21, "Self-Control Training", October 17, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0318)
    Guest lecturer: Claire Barabash; Air date: November 6, 1977
  - Episode #22, "Behavioral Management, Part I", October 24, 1977 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0329)
    Guest lecturer: Dr. Evelyn Kurtzberg; Air date: November 7, 1977
  - Episode #23, "Behavioral Management, Part II", October 26, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0315)
    Guest lecturer: Dr. Evelyn Kurtzberg; Air date: November 9, 1977
  - Episode #24, "Related Issues and Conclusions", October 24, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0295)
    Air date: November 11, 1977
  - Episode #25, "Insight-Directed Techniques: Relevant Concepts", October 31, 1977 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0321)
    Air date: November 14, 1977
  - Episode #26, "Psychodynamic Principles", October 31, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0307)
    Guest lecturer: Dr. Irme Siller; Air date: November 16, 1977
  - Episode #27, "Talking, Feelings and Control", October 31, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0285)
    Guest lecturer: Dr. Ester Buchholz; Air date: November 18, 1977
  - Episode #29, "Group Discussion and Student Behavior, Continued", November 14, 1977 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0326)
    Guest lecturer: Dr. Susan Frame; Air date: November 23, 1977
  - Episode #30, "Related Issues and Conclusions", November 10, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0297)
    Guest lecturer: Dorothy Griffith; Air date: November 25, 1977
  - Episode #31, "Social Processes: Relevant Concepts", November 10, 1977 (Box 1, Audiocassette 7.3.1.1.0284)
    Air date: November 28, 1977
  - Episode #32, "Social Problem-Solving Techniques", November 16, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0311)
    Guest lecturer: Edward Trieber; Air date: November 30, 1977
  - Episode #33, "Social Problem-Solving Approaches for Teachers", November 14, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0290)
    Guest lecturer: Judith Alpert; Air date: December 2, 1977
  - Episode #34, "The School as a Social System", November 21, 1977 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0327)
    Guest lecturer: Judith Alpert; Air date: December 5, 1977
  - Episode #35, "The Prepared Environment", November 21, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0308)
    Guest lecturer: Eleanor Dimoff; Air date: December 7, 1977
  - Episode #36, "Social Control", November 21, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0317)
    Guest lecturer: Dr. Joseph Giacquinta; Air date: December 9, 1977
  - Episode #37, "School Curriculum: Part I", December 1, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0301)
    Air date: December 12, 1977
  - Episode #37 -- Air Copy, December 1, 1977; cuid18701 (Box 53, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0511)
  - Episode #37 -- Standby Copy, December 1, 1977; cuid18688 (Box 54, 2 inch videoreel 7.3.1.1.0491)
  - Episode #38, "School Curriculum: Part II", December 1, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0312)
    Air date: December 14, 1977
  - Episode #39, "Learning as Discipline", December 1, 1977 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0328)
    Air date: December 16, 1977
  - Episode #40, "Control Problems and the Exceptional Child", December 5, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0296)
    Guest lecturer: Dr. Sheldon Kastner; Air date: December 19, 1977
  - Episode #42, "Special Settings Continued", December 5, 1977 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0330)
    Guest lecturers: Dr. Judith Kranes and Mimi Lawin; Air date: December 23, 1977
  - Episode #43, "Guidance: Special Problems", December 19, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0309)
    Guest lecturers: Dr. Judith Kranes and Anne Wright; Air date: December 28, 1977
  - Episode #44, "Related Issues and Conclusions", December 19, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0287)
    Guest lecturers: Elizabeth [Gwendolyn] Jones and Alexander Faber; Air date: December 30, 1977
  - Episode #45, "The Future", October 17, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0302)
    Guest lecturers: Albert Shanker and Dr. Irwin Hyman; Air date: January 4, 1978
  - Episode #46, "Semester Wrap-Up", December 19, 1977 (Box 1, Quarter inch audio reel 7.3.1.1.0300)